Guide to the Records of The Bolivia Project RISM RG 8
New York University Archives
- Series IV. Epidemiological Research Records
  - Subseries J. Laboratory Results/ Pruebas de Laboratorio
    - La Paz Maternidad Hospital, undated (Box 211, Folder 2)
    - La Paz -- Caja Nacional, undated (Box 211, Folder 3)
    - La Paz -- Thorax Institute, undated (Box 211, Folder 4)
    - Penas -- Catecus 9P, undated (Box 211, Folder 5)
    - Penas -- Catacora, undated (Box 211, Folder 6)
    - Penas Esquillani, undated (Box 211, Folder 7)
    - Penas -- Pajcha, undated (Box 211, Folder 8)
    - Penas, undated (Box 211, Folder 9)
    - Coroico School, undated (Box 212, Folder 1)
    - Coroico School, 1965 (Box 212, Folder 2)
    - Coroico School, 1965 (Box 212, Folder 3)
    - Coroico School, 1965 (Box 212, Folder 4)
    - Reyes School, undated (Box 212, Folder 5)
    - Reyes School, 1965 (Box 212, Folder 5)
    - Reyes School, 1965 (Box 212, Folder 7)
    - Compi School, undated (Box 212, Folder 8)
    - Compi School, 1965 (Box 212, Folder 9)
  - Subseries K. Tuberculin Surveys
    See Laboratory Results
    This subseries consists of 3,531 surveys documenting test results for members of 1,186 households in the communities noted in Subseries J. The forms include personal information of individuals and reactions to the tuberculin tests. The surveys are indexed by the Member of the Household Number.
- Series V. Ethnographic Research Records
  The materials in this series relate to the ethnographic study undertaken between 1964 and 1967. The final report was published in 1969 as Changing Rural Bolivia. The report was republished in 1971 by Oxford University Press as Changing Rural Society. The materials have been divided into five subseries.
  - Subseries A. Household Structure Diagram/Bosquejo de Casa
    This subseries consists of 122 forms arranged by the name of the head of household. These documents are stored with the Household Administrative Card-Household Sanitation, Tuberculin Surveys, and Laboratory Results in the Epidemiological Research Material. The Household Structure Diagram was used to register information regarding kinship.
  - Subseries B. Changing Rural Society
    - Changing Rural Bolivia, 1969 (Box 213, Folder 1)
    - Changing Rural Society manuscript and photos: Oxford University Press, undated (Box 213, Folder 2)
    - Curriculum vitae, 1971-1983 (Box 213, Folder 3)
    - Bolivia Oxford Contract and Statements (empty) (Box 213, Folder 4)
    - Bolivia Correspondence Oxford (empty), undated (Box 213, Folder 5)
  - Subseries C. Community Census/ Censo de la Comunidad
    This subseries consists of 161 census forms. This census, undertaken in San Miguel and Sorata, includes the names of the people interviewed, which may also be referenced in the Biographical Index. The census material also includes information about family members, language, education and status in the community.
  - Subseries D. Community Study Outline (CSO)/ Bosquejo para el estudio de las Communidades
    This subseries consists of the Community Study Outline (CSO)/Bosquejo para el estudio de las communidades. The CSO is an outline that was used to standardize and index the information recorded in the field notes generated by each anthropologist. The one exception is Compi, where the anthropologists were already present in the community conducting their own research. For Compi, only Biographical Index and Member of Household Number designations exist. These forms document geographic environment, population demographics, history and development, institutional systems, the sociopolitical system, community and private health, and the Peace Corps program.
  - Subseries E. Field Notes / Notas de Campo
    This subseries consists of 14,000 pages and 30 bound volumes of field notes, organized by community and fieldworker. The field notes were processed by a team of data coders and analysts, who produced the CSO Indexed Field Notes Cards and the Biographical Index.
    Each fieldworker is identified by his or her initials. A list of fieldworkers by community may be found below.
    Fieldworkers by Community
    Reconnaissance: William J. McEwen (WJM)
    Reconnaissance: Dwight B. Heath (DBH)
    Reconnaissance: Victor C. Novick (VCN)
    Compi: Hans Buechler (HB)
    Compi: Pascual Nacho (PN)
    Coroico: Alfredo Antezana (AAG)
    Coroico: Katherine Barnes (KJB)
    Coroico: Dwight Heath (DBH)
    Coroico: Felix Mangudo (FMC)
    Coroico: Eloy Robalino (EARS)
    Reyes: Alejandro Madde (AMJ)
    Reyes: Said Madde (SMJ)
    Reyes: Rene Mendoza (RMS)
    Reyes: Victor Novick (VCN)
    Reyes: Gwen Novick (GN)
    Reyes: Gerardo Pereira (GPR)
    Reyes: Julio Roca (JRJ)
    San Miguel: Lauren Klein (LCK)
    San Miguel: Marcos Mamani (MM)
    San Miguel: Solomon Miller (SM)
    Sorata: Katherine Barnes (KJB)
    Sorata: Eustaquio Condori (ECT)
    Sorata: Beverly Holcombe (BJH)
    Sorata: Mauricio Mamani (MMP)
    Sorata: William McEwen (WJM)
    Sorata: Paz Mejia (PMM)
    Sorata: Eloy Robalino (EARS)
    Sorata: Fernando Varela (FVB)
    Sorata: Jaime Vilela (JVS)
    Sorata: Fredy Penalosa (FPO)
    Villa Abecia: Katherine Barnes (KJB)
    Villa Abecia: Carlos Avila (CAB)
    Villa Abecia: Roso Avila (RAB)
    Villa Abecia: Said Madde (SMH)
    Villa Abecia: Victor Novick (VCN)
    - Reconnaissance (1 Volume): WJM (1:1 - 14:8), 1964 (Box 214)
    - DBH (0.0 - 44:4), undated (Box 214)
    - VCN (7:1 - 10:1), undated (Box 214)
    - Compi: HB (1 - 332), undated (Box 215)
    - HB (333 - 418; Records/Appendixes), undated (Box 216)
    - Coroico: AAG (1 - 163), undated (Box 217)
    - FMC (Cruz Loma 1 - 271), 1965 (Box 218)
    - FMC (1 - 240), 1964-1965 (Box 219)
    - FMC (241 - 465), 1965 (Box 220)
    - EARS (1 - 300), 1965 (Box 221)
    - EARS (301 - 600), undated (Box 222)
    - EARS (601-900), undated (Box 173)
    - EARS (901 - 1200), undated (Box 223)
    - EARS (1201 - 1536), 1965 (Box 224)
    - KJB (1 - 270), 1965 (Box 225)
    - KJB (271 - 540), 1965 (Box 226)
    - KJB (541 - 811), 1965 (Box 227)
    - DBH (1 - 300), 1964-1965 (Box 228)
    - DBH (301 - 600), 1965 (Box 229)
    - DBH (601 - 852), 1965 (Box 230)
    - Roger Newman (Mururata), 1965 (Box 231)
    - Reyes: JRI (1 - 68), 1965 (Box 232)
    - AMJ (1 - 90), 1965 (Box 232)
    - RMS (1 - 47), 1965 (Box 232)
    - GPR (1 - 189), 1965 (Box 233)
    - SMJ (1 - 330), 1965 (Box 234)
    - SMJ (331 - 657), 1965 (Box 235)
    - GN (1 - 312), 1965 (Box 236)
    - VCN (1 - 300), 1964 (Box 237)
    - VCN (301 - 600), 1965 (Box 238)
    - VCN (601 - 891), 1965 (Box 239)
    - San Miguel: LCK (1 - 340), 1965 (Box 240)
    - SM (1 - 368), 1966 (Box 241)
    - Sorata: FPO (1 - 217), 1965 (Box 242)
    - MMP (1 - 14), 1965 (Box 242)
    - ECT (1 - 91), 1965 (Box 242)
    - KJB (1 - 260), 1966 (Box 243)
    - KJB (261 - 523), 1966 (Box 244)
    - BJH (1 - 300), 1965 (Box 245)
    - BJH (301 - 600), 1965 (Box 246)
    - BJH (601 - 901), 1966 (Box 247)
    - PMM (1 - 340), 1966 (Box 248)
    - PMM (341 - 680), 1966 (Box 249)
    - JVS (1 - 300), 1966 (Box 250)
    - JVS (301 - 600), 1966 (Box 251)
    - JVS (601 - 891), 1966 (Box 252)
    - EARS (1 - 320), 1966 (Box 253)
    - EARS (321 - 640), 1966 (Box 254)
    - FVB (1 - 237), 1966 (Box 255)
    - Villa Abecia: RAB (1 - 244), 1966 (Box 256)
    - CAB (1 - 250), 1966 (Box 257)
    - CAB (251 - 502), 1966 (Box 258)
    - VCN (1 - 350), 1965 (Box 259)
    - VCN (1 - 250) -- copy, 1965 (Box 260)
    - VCN (351 - 497; Records/Appendixes), 1966 (Box 261)
    - VCN (251 - 497) -- copy, 1966 (Box 262)
    - KJB (1 - 230), 1965 (Box 263)
    - KJB (231 - 468), 1966 (Box 264)
    - SMJ (1 - 300), 1965 (Box 265)
    - SMJ (301 - 632), 1966 (Box 266)
- Series VI. Surveys and Questionnaires
  The materials in this series have been divided into two subseries.
  - Subseries A. Attitudinal Questionnaire /Cedula de Creencias
    Subseries A contains 229 Attitudinal Questionnaires/Cedulas de Creencias. These questionnaires have been organized by community and include the names of persons who were interviewed. These names may also appear in the Biographical Index.
    - Coroico (147), undated (Box 267)
    - Reyes (82), 1965 (Box 268)
    - Sorata, undated (Box 269)
  - Subseries B. Household Social Survey / Encuesta sobre la Comunidad (1,094)
    Subseries B contains 1,094 Household Social Surveys/Encuestas sobre la Communidad. These surveys have not been fully analyzed or indexed with other materials in the collection. Some materials were processed and analyzed by Jonathan L. Kelley and Herbert S. Klein for their study Revolution and the Rebirth of Inequality, published in 1981.
    - Compi, 1966 (Box 270-271)
    - Coroico, 1966 (Box 272-278)
    - Reyes, undated (Box 279-287)
    - Reyes / Sorata, 1966 (Box 288)
    - Villa Abecia / Reyes, undated (Box 289)
    - San Miguel, 1966 (Box 290-292)
    - Sorata, 1966 (Box 293-299)
    - Capilaya, 1966 (Box 300-301)
    - Villa Abecia, 1966 (Box 302-303)
- Series VII. Microfiche: CSO Indexed Field Note Cards, undated (Box 304)
  - Microfiche: CSO Indexed Field Note Cards, undated (Box 304)
- Series VIII. Microfilm: Biographical Index Cards, undated (Box 305)
  - Microfilm: Biographical Index Cards, undated (Box 305)
- Series IX. Project Reports
  This series includes reports written by field investigators, proposals, quarterly reports sent to the Peace Corps, articles related to Bolivia, community studies, and reference materials, all arranged by author's last name. Please note that some reports are duplicated in Series I. Correspondence.
  - Subseries A. Ethnographic Studies
    - Buechler, Hans. Agrarian Reform and Migration on the Bolivian Altiplano, undated (Box NA, Item 1)
    - Buechler, Judith-Maria. A Study on Child Development on the Bolivian Altiplano., undated (Box NA, Item 2)
    - Comitas, Lambros. Education and Social Stratification in Contemporary Bolivia (Box NA, Item 3)
    - Heath, Dwight B. Revolution and Stability in Bolivia, undated (Box NA, Item 4)
    - Research Proposal submitted to the Peace Corps. /Public Health Research in Bolivia, undated (Box NA, Item 5)
    - Quarterly Reports of the Peace Corps. Studyman Project in Bolivia Issues 1 - 9, undated-1966 (Box NA, Item 6)
    - Leons, Madeline B. The Role of Government in the Economic Development of Latin America, undated (Box NA, Item 7)
    - McEwen, William J. Variations in Political Involvement in Contrasting Bolivian Communities., undated (Box NA, Item 8)
    - Muratorio, Blanca. Changing Bases of Social Stratification in a Bolivian Community, undated (Box NA, Item 9)
    - Muratorio, Blanca. Social and Political Participation of the Nor Yungas Campesinos, undated (Box NA, Item 10)
    - Novick, Victor. Too Many Indians Not Enough Chiefs: Leadership Crisis in a Bolivian Hacienda Town, undated (Box NA, Item 11)
    - Sorimshaw, Susan. Background and Proposal for Field Work, undated (Box NA, Item 12)
  - Subseries B. Epidemiological Studies:
    - Maru Sera Sample - Total Epidemiological Sample, undated (Box NA, Item 13)
    - Community Health Studies, undated (Box NA, Item 14)
    - Original Figures and References, undated (Box NA, Item 15)
    - Acknowledgments and References, undated (Box NA, Item 16)
    - Technical Report on the Epidemiological Study, undated (Box NA, Item 17)
- Series X. Unpublished Manuscripts
  The materials in this series have been arranged alphabetically by author's name. This series has been organized into two subseries.
  - Subseries A. Student Papers
    Scope and Content
    The materials in this subseries consist of student papers prepared by students from Columbia University and the University of Kentucky. Students developed these papers during summer fieldwork studies conducted by by Dr. Lambros Comitas, Assistant Director of the Research Institute for the Study of Man.
    Conditions Governing Access
    Please be aware that FERPA guidelines may prevent access to student materials in the absence of a signed release form.
    - Local Government in Bolivia: Public Administration and Popular Participation, Adrianne Aron, undated (Box 306, Folder 1)
    - Realities of Bolivian Education, Bambi Bernhard, 1966 (Box 306, Folder 2)
    - Agrarian Reform and Migration Migration (Section I - The Community Level) Hans C. Buechler, undated (Box 306, Folder 3)
    - Agrarian Reform and Migration (Section II. The Family Level) Hans C. Buechler, undated (Box 306, Folder 4)
    - Tentative Outline of Master's Thesis Essay and Draft Essay: A Study of Child Development in a Bolivian Altiplano Community, Judith-Maria Buechler, undated (Box 306, Folder 5)
    - A Study of Child Development on the Bolivian Altiplano [Chapter 1 missing], Judith-Maria Buechler, undated (Box 306, Folder 6)
    - A Study of Child Development on the Bolivian Altiplano [pp. 1 - 70], Judith-Maria Buechler, undated (Box 306, Folder 7)
    - A Study of Child Development on the Bolivian Altiplano [pp. 71 - 161], Judith-Maria Buechler, undated (Box 306, Folder 8)
    - Coroico, Bolivia, Rachel Eubank, 1966 (Box 306, Folder 9)
    - The Development of Bolivian Rural Education, 1900 - 1969, John Francis Hohenstein, 1970 (Box 307, Folder 1)
    - A Community Health Study of Reyes, Bolivia, David Lawrence, 1967 (Box 307, Folder 2)
    - Draft essay: Aymara Folkmedicine: Folk Medicine in Huatajata, Bolivia, William J. Mitchell, undated (Box 307, Folder 3)
    - Folk Medicine in Huatajata, Bolivia, William J. Mitchell, 1967 (Box 307, Folder 4)
    - Inter-Group Relations in Highland Bolivia, Roger C. Newman, 1965 (Box 307, Folder 5)
    - Land Reform in Bolivia's Yungas, Roger C. Newman, undated (Box 307, Folder 6)
    - Local Health Study of Villa Abecia, Bolivia, Patterned After WHO Recommendations for Community Study, Edwin G. Nighbert, 1965 (Box 307, Folder 7)
    - Analysis of Infant Feeding Practices in Sorata, Bolivia, Susan Scrimshaw, 1966 (Box 307, Folder 8)
    - Outline of Local Health Study of Compi, Bolivia, Paul W. Wright, 1965 (Box 307, Folder 9)
  - Subseries B. Conference and Working Papers
    The materials in this subseries consist of conference papers organized by field directors in Bolivia.
    - The United States and the Bolivian Revolution (1952 - 1964), Cole Blasier, undated (Box 308, Folder 1)
    - Processes of Bolivian Syndicalism: A Reinterpretation of the Relationship Between Social Behavior and Institutions, Hans Buechler, 1970 (Box 308, Folder 2)
    - The Effect of the Bolivian Land Reform Upon Human Resources in the Lake Titicaca Region, Melvin Burke, undated (Box 308, Folder 3)
    - The Bolivian Aymara and Social Change: A Reevaluation of the "Culture Broker" Concept, Hans Christian and Judith-Maria Buechler, 1969 (Box 308, Folder 4)
    - Revolution and the Agrarian Sector, William E. Carter, undated (Box 308, Folder 5)
    - Bolivia in Time of Revolution, Holy Week 1952, Carter Goodrich, undated (Box 308, Folder 6)
    - Biculturalism: The Aymara Case, John M. Hickman, 1968 (Box 308, Folder 7)
    - Prelude to the Revolution, Herbert S. Klein, undated (Box 308, Folder 8)
    - Continuity and Discontinuity in Peasant Economics in the Province of Nor Yungas, Bolivia, Madeline Barbara Leons and William Leons, undated (Box 308, Folder 9)
    - The Bolivian Novel, The Chaco War, and the Revolution, Murdo J. Macleod, undated (Box 308, Folder 10)
    - Bolivia's MNR: A Study of a National Popular Movement in Latin America, James M. Malloy, 1968 (Box 308, Folder 11)
    - Revolutionary Politics in Bolivia, James M. Malloy, 1969 (Box 308, Folder 12)
    - On Analyzing the Sociometric Information in the Bolivia Project Questionnaire, Frank Many [?], 1966 (Box 308, Folder 13)
    - Social Change and National Integration in Bolivia, William J. McEwen, undated (Box 308, Folder 14)
    - Theory and Methodology of the RISM Bolivia Project, William J. McEwen, undated (Box 309, Folder 1)
    - Education in Bolivia, Robert G. Myers, 1969 (Box 309, Folder 2)
    - Changing Bases of Social Stratification in a Bolivian Community, Blanca Muratorio, 1966 (Box 309, Folder 3)
    - Revolutionary Change in a Bolivian Hacienda Town, Victor Novick, 1966 (Box 309, Folder 4)
    - Too Many Indians, Not Enough Chiefs: Leadership Crisis in a Bolivian Hacienda Town, Victor Novick, undated (Box 309, Folder 5)
    - San Carlos -- Camba Town, Allyn MacLean Stearman, 1971 (Box 309, Folder 6)
    - Las Realidades de la Educacion Primaria En Bolivia, Senior Alberto Tardio, 1967 (Box 309, Folder 7)
    - Bolivia: The Economic Transformtion, Richard S. Thorn, 1969 (Box 309, Folder 8)
    - Bolivia's Public Financial Policy and Foreign Trade Since 1952, James W. Wilkie, 1969 (Box 309, Folder 9)
    - Bolivia in the 1970s: What Kind of Revolution?, Bernard M. Wood, undated (Box 309, Folder 10)
    - La Organizacion Nuclear En Bolivia, Carlos A. Vildozo, undated (Box 309, Folder 11)
    - Los Estudiantes Y La Universidad "Estudio de Actitudes" (Investi-gacion Preliminar), Centro De Investigation, Instituto Bolivano De Estudios Y Accion Social (I.B.E.A.S), 1966 (Box 309, Folder 12)
    - Notes on Bolivian study areas, undated (Box 309, Folder 13)
    - Notes on Bolivian study areas, undated (Box 309, Folder 14)
    - Miscellaneous notes, undated (Box 309, Folder 15)
- Series XI. Community and Regional Maps
  This series consists of 15 maps, arranged chronologically. Most of the maps in this series were hand drawn and provide details of the communities being studied. The maps were also used for planting purposes and for building.
  - Plano General De La Comunidad "Tauca" Provinicia Omasuyos Canton Stgo De Huata, Feb 1957 (Box NA, Item 1)
  - Plano General De La Comunidad "Tauca" Provinicia Omasuyos Canton Stgo De Huata, Feb 1957 (Box NA, Item 2)
  - Plano Parcelario y Replanteo de La Propiedad, Compi, Apr 1958 (Box NA, Item 3)
  - Plano Parcelario y Replanteo de La C omunidad Capilaya, undated (Box NA, Item 4)
  - Plano Parcial De La Hacienda "Compi", undated (Box NA, Item 5)
  - Plano Parcial De La Hacienda "Compi", Aug 1964 (Box NA, Item 6)
  - Plano Parcelario De "Compi" Amasi, Oct 1965? (Box NA, Item 7)
  - Plano Parcelario De "Compi", undated (Box NA, Item 8)
  - Plano Parcelario De Capilaya, undated (Box NA, Item 9)
  - Plano Parcelario De Capilaya, undated (Box NA, Item 10)
  - Plano General De Sorata, undated (Box NA, Item 11)
  - Map of Communidad Llamacachi, undated (Box NA, Item 12)
  - Map of Llamachi, undated (Box NA, Item 13)
  - Map of Villa Abecia, undated (Box NA, Item 14)
  - Map of Coroico, undated (Box NA, Item 15)
- Series XII. Photographs
  This series consists of black-and-white and color photos of varying sizes and contact sheets in 2 photo albums. The pictures depict urban and rural landscapes, indigenous costumes, celebrations and festivals, musicians, market scenes, religious ceremonies, population and interaction between the indigenous population and members of the RISM epidemiology team. Among those credited with taking the photos are Kay Barnes and Victor Novick in Villa Abecia, William McEwen in Sorota, Herbert Klein in San Miguel, K. Barnes and D.B. Heath in Coroico, and Victor Novick in Reyes. Dr. Lambros Comitas provided general photo coverage. A number of photographs were contributed by Dr. Vera D. Rubin.
  - Villa Abecia, Sorota, San Miguel, Coroico, Reyes, undated (Box 310)
  - Studyman, 1964-1968 (Box 311)
- Series XIII. Miscellaneous Papers
  This series consists of 0.5 linear feet, arranged chronologically. This series contains articles, tables, charts and notes that relate to the Project's research goals. Some material is duplicated in Series I. Correspondence.
  - Estudios Socio Economico en las Provincias de Omasuyos, Inganin (sp) y Los Andes, La Paz, 1946 (Box NA, Item 1)
  - Censo General de Bolivia, 1950 (Box NA, Item 2)
  - Monografia Estadistic Indigena de Bolivia with maps, undated (Box NA, Item 3)
  - Bolivia's Adventure in Learning, Natural History, Dec 1954 (Box NA, Item 4)
  - Cuentos Nacionales y Cuadros Estadisticos, 1958-1964 (Box NA, Item 5)
  - CEP Boletin Informativo, Centro de Estudios de Poblacion; Bibliografia de Articulos Sobre Los Indios Bolivianos en Revistas Y Periodicos; population maps, Jul 1959; Oct 1968, undated (Box NA, Item 6)
  - Siles Zuazo, Herman4 Anos de Gob Rev. 1956 - 1960 Bolivia Edit. Del Estado Sin [?] (Box NA, Item 7)
  - Boletin Estadistico, 1960 (Box NA, Item 8)
  - Boletin Estadistico, 1962 (Box NA, Item 9)
  - Boletin Estadistico, 1963 (Box NA, Item 10)
  - Cuadros Estadisticos para la Encuesta Demografia y de Vivienda, Apr 1963 (Box NA, Item 11)
  - V. Paz Estenssoro, Mensage al Congreso, undated (Box NA, Item 12)
  - Journal entry about Peace Corps. workers in Sorata, undated (Box NA, Item 13)
  - Preliminary program for Seminar on Anthropology of the Andes and Its Environs, undated (Box NA, Item 14)
  - Facultad De Servicio Social, undated (Box NA, Item 15)
  - Education references in Bolivia Studyman [?], undated (Box NA, Item 16)
  - Notes: Finot - Sobre El Problema del Indio, undated (Box NA, Item 17)
  - Notes on various Bolivian communities, undated (Box NA, Item 18)
  - Notes, tables and charts, undated (Box NA, Item 19)
  - Tables and charts, undated (Box NA, Item 20)
  - Tables and charts, undated (Box NA, Item 21)
  - Type and Content of Archives, undated (Box 312, Folder 1)
  - Type and content of archives, undated (Box 312, Folder 1)
  - Memorandum, 1997 (Box 312, Folder 2)
  - Curatorial computer files, 1997 (Box 312, Folder 3)
  - Community study outline, undated (Box 312, Folder 4)
  - Promotional materials: Retrospect and Prospect: Preservation and Use of Archival Materials in the Digital Age, 1997 (Box 312, Folder 5)
  - Photocopied materials re: Peace Corps/RISM Bolivia project, 1964-1966 (Box 312, Folder 6)
  - Bolivia Project General Inventory, 1997 (Box 312, Folder 7)
  - Bolivia Film Strips: U.S. Productions: Legal Correspondence, 1967 (Box 312, Folder 8)
  - Bolivia--Description & Travel, undated (Box 312, Folder 8)
  - Epidemiological Studies in Bolivia: Sorata, Atahuallpani, A1-15, 1964 (Box 312, Folder 9)
  - Unlabeled, 1965 (Box 312, Folder 10)
  - Epidemiological Studies in Bolivia: Reviews, 1972-1975 (Box 312, Folder 11)
  - Changing Rural Bolivia: Reviews, 1970-1976 (Box 312, Folder 12)
  - 1946, undated (Box 313, Folder 1)
  - 1950, undated (Box 313, Folder 2)
  - 1954, undated (Box 313, Folder 3)
  - December 1954 (Box 313, Folder 4)
  - 1958-1964 (Box 313, Folder 5)
  - July 1959; October 1968; undated, 1959-1968 (Box 313, Folder 6)
  - 1960, undated (Box 313, Folder 7)
  - 1960, undated (Box 313, Folder 8)
  - 1962 (Box 313, Folder 9)
  - 1963 (Box 313, Folder 10)
  - April 1963 (Box 313, Folder 11)
  - 1964 (Box 313, Folder 12)
  - September 1965 (Box 313, Folder 13)
  - November 1969 (Box 313, Folder 14)
  - Unlabeled, undated (Box 313, Folder 15)
  - Unlabeled, undated (Box 313, Folder 16)
  - Unlabeled, undated (Box 313, Folder 17)
  - Unlabeled, undated (Box 313, Folder 18)
  - Unlabeled, undated (Box 313, Folder 19)
  - Unlabeled, undated (Box 313, Folder 20)
  - Unlabeled, undated (Box 313, Folder 21)
- Appendix: Audiovisual Materials
  Partly as a result of the RISM Bolivia Project (1964-1967), the United States Office of Education in 1968 and 1969 sponsored a study of rural education in Argentina, Bolivia, and Jamaica. The principal investigator of this study was Lambros Comitas, then Professor of Anthropology and Education at Teachers College, Columbia University, and Associate Director of the Research Institute for the Study of Man.
  The Bolivia CV Recordings, an integral part of this comparative study, were taped by Lambros Comitas in 1969 using a Sony Videocorder and CV reel-to-reel videotape for helican scan video recorders.
  - 16 mm film -- unlabeled, undated (Box 314, Item 1)
  - 16 mm film -- "Fable test" (2 copies), undated (Box 314, Item 2)